<idea-plugin>
  <id>io.github.avaxerrr.qsstoolkit</id>
  <name>QSS Toolkit</name>
  <vendor>avaxerrr</vendor>
  <description><![CDATA[
    <h2>QSS Toolkit: Complete Qt Style Sheet Support for PyCharm and IntelliJ-based IDEs</h2>

    <p>QSS Toolkit adds comprehensive Qt Style Sheet editing capabilities to PyCharm and other IntelliJ-based IDEs with Python support, providing all the modern tools you need for professional Qt application styling.</p>

    <h3>Key Features:</h3>
    <ul>
      <li><b>Syntax Highlighting</b> - Specialized highlighting for Qt selectors, properties, pseudo-states, and color values</li>
      <li><b>Integrated Color Tools</b> - In-editor color picker with gutter previews for hex color values</li>
      <li><b>Smart Code Completion</b> - Context-aware suggestions for Qt widgets, properties, and values</li>
      <li><b>Color Palette Management</b> - Create, save, copy and reuse colors across your Qt projects</li>
      <li><b>Structure Navigation</b> - Hierarchical view of selectors and properties for quick navigation</li>
      <li><b>Code Folding</b> - Collapse complex selectors and property blocks for better readability</li>
    </ul>

    <h3>IDE Compatibility:</h3>
    <p>This plugin works with PyCharm (Community and Professional) and any IntelliJ-based IDE with the Python plugin installed, including IntelliJ IDEA.</p>

    <h3>Why QSS Toolkit?</h3>
    <p>This plugin integrates seamlessly into your development environment, maintaining your workflow while adding specialized tools for Qt styling.</p>

    <p>Perfect for Qt developers who want to enhance productivity and code quality when styling Qt applications in Python projects.</p>

    <h3>Getting Started</h3>
    <p>Simply install the plugin and open any .qss file. All features are immediately available with no additional configuration required.</p>
]]></description>



  <!-- Product and plugin compatibility requirements -->
  <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>
  <depends>com.intellij.modules.lang</depends>
  <depends>com.intellij.modules.python</depends>

  <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
    <!-- File type registration -->
    <fileType name="QSS" implementationClass="io.github.avaxerrr.qsstoolkit.QssFileType"
              language="QSS" extensions="qss"/>

    <!-- Syntax highlighter -->
    <lang.syntaxHighlighterFactory language="QSS"
                                   implementationClass="io.github.avaxerrr.qsstoolkit.highlighting.QssSyntaxHighlighterFactory"/>

    <!-- Parser definition -->
    <lang.parserDefinition language="QSS"
                           implementationClass="io.github.avaxerrr.qsstoolkit.parser.QssParserDefinition"/>

    <!-- Color annotator -->
    <annotator language="QSS"
               implementationClass="io.github.avaxerrr.qsstoolkit.highlighting.QssColorAnnotator"/>

    <!-- Completion contributor -->
    <completion.contributor language="QSS"
                            implementationClass="io.github.avaxerrr.qsstoolkit.completion.QssCompletionContributor"/>

    <!-- Code folding -->
    <lang.foldingBuilder language="QSS"
                         implementationClass="io.github.avaxerrr.qsstoolkit.folding.QssFoldingBuilder"/>

    <!-- Structure view -->
    <lang.psiStructureViewFactory language="QSS"
                                  implementationClass="io.github.avaxerrr.qsstoolkit.structure.QssStructureViewFactory"/>

    <!-- Color palette tool window -->
    <toolWindow id="QSS Colors" secondary="true" icon="AllIcons.Toolwindows.ToolWindowPalette" anchor="right"
                factoryClass="io.github.avaxerrr.qsstoolkit.palette.QssColorPaletteToolWindowFactory"/>
  </extensions>
</idea-plugin>
